<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Lords Justices, a proclamation declaring the Parliament shall be prorogued until the twenty eighth day of July next. Tho. Cantuar. J. Sommers C.S. Pembroke C.P.S. Devonshire. Shrewsbury. Dorset. Godolphin. Whereas this present Parliament stands prorogued to the sixteenth day of June next, ...</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Lords Justices.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 2KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B21808</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99884491</idno>
  <idno type="VID">190909</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240882488</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E947</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 21.h.3[187]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R215388</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99884491</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99884491e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B21808)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 190909)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement C24:1[187])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Lords Justices, a proclamation declaring the Parliament shall be prorogued until the twenty eighth day of July next. Tho. Cantuar. J. Sommers C.S. Pembroke C.P.S. Devonshire. Shrewsbury. Dorset. Godolphin. Whereas this present Parliament stands prorogued to the sixteenth day of June next, ...</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Lords Justices.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by Charles Bill, and the executrix of Thomas Newcomb, deceas'd, printers to the Kings most excellent Majesty,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1696.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"Parliament, now prorogued to 16 June, is further prorogued till 28 July. Not necessary to come up for prorogation. Notice will be given of the meeting." -- Steele.</note>
                  <note>Title from caption and opening words of text.</note>
                  <note>At end: Given at the Council Chamber the eighteenth day of May, 1696. In the eighth year of His Majesties reign.</note>
                  <note>Steele notation: to Attend of; Arms 125.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">England and Wales. --  Parliament --  Rules and practice --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  William and Mary, 1689-1702 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-12 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-12 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="royal_proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:190909:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <head>W R</head>
                  <figDesc>English royal blazon surmounted by a crown and flanked by the English lion and Tudor rose on one side and the Scottish unicorn and thistle on the other</figDesc>
                  <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <q xml:lang="frm">DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>By the Lords Justices, A PROCLAMATION Declaring the PARLIAMENT shall be Prorogued until the Twenty eighth Day of <hi>July</hi> next.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>Tho. Cantuar.</item>
                     <item>J. Sommers <hi>C.S.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Pembroke <hi>C.P.S.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Devonshire.</item>
                     <item>Shrewsbury.</item>
                     <item>Dorset.</item>
                     <item>Godolphin.</item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s present Parliament stands Prorogued to the Sixteénth Day of <hi>June</hi> next, We, by the Advice of His Majesties Privy Council, for weighty reasons Vs especially moving, do hereby Publish and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare, That the same Parliament shall, upon the said Sixteénth Day of <hi>June,</hi> be further Prorogued unto the Twenty eighth Day of <hi>July</hi> next ensuing; Whereof the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and the Knights, Citizens and Burgesses of the House of Commons, and all others whom it may Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern, may hereby take Notice: We letting them know, That it will not be expected that any should Attend at the said Sixteénth Day of <hi>June</hi> next, but such as being in and about the Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Westminster</hi> may Attend the Making of the said Prorogation, in such manner as heretofore in like Cases hath beén Accustomed. And We do hereby further Declare, That convenient Notice shall be giv<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n by Proclamation of the Time when the Parliament shall Meét and Sit for the Dispatch of Business, to the End that the Members of both Houses may Order their Affairs accordingly.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given at the Council Chamber <date>the Eighteenth Day of <hi>May,</hi> 1696. In the Eight Year of His Majesties Reign.</date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/> God save the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>Charles Bill,</hi> and the Executrix of <hi>Thomas Newcomb,</hi> deceas'd, Printers to the Kings most Excellent Majesty. 1696.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:190909:2"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>